

Alexander Meuer

Polyglot Developer

alex@alexmeuer.com

alexmeuer.com

linkedin.com/in/alexmeuer

github.com/alexmeuer

stackoverflow.com/u/4571656

Pragmatic and diligent developer who takes pride in his work. I've worked across many facets of software, game, and app development. I'm quick to learn and happy to pick up new skills along the way. I'm confident in my abilities to self-motivate and work effectively in a distributed team.

SKILLS





Flutter

Google Cloud Platform

GraphOL

Redis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Qualio 🗷

04/2022 - Present

Remote, Ireland

Remote, Ireland

Full-stack development for a large med-tech company.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Contributed to both team-specific frontends as well as taking ownership of a shared component library to solve UI/UX inconsistencies across a range of micro-frontends.
- Built well-tested features across the full stack, with a focus on clean architecture and appropriate separation of concerns.
- Pushed for improved code quality through informal dev talks and more careful code reviews/pairing.
- Proposed (and then implemented) a team git branching strategy and hooks to ensure readable history and organised repo.

Chief Technology Officer

Off The Court

11/2020 - Present Developed a mentorship platform for US NCAA college athletes.

Achievements/Tasks

- Created a Go-powered backend on top of GraphQL to iterate rapidly in order to hit our go-to-market deadline.
- Leveraged Kubernetes and Hasura GraphQL's action & event systems to set up an async pipeline and ensure massive scalability.
- Developed the Go backend as isolated modules, so that they'd be easier to test and maintain.
- Made time-critical and finance-critical decisions concerning all aspects of technology for the company.

Flutter Developer

Articulate.xyz 🗷

07/2020 - 12/2020 Flutter MVP Development

Remote, United Kingdom

Achievements/Tasks

- Converted an iOS MVP into a well-tested cross-platform Flutter app.
- Advised on CI/CD best practices as well as scalability.
- Lead the technical aspects of the hiring process.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Game Developer

Yakuto Ltd 🗷

05/2018 - 07/2020 London, United Kingdom

Unity Mobile Game Development

- Achievements/Tasks
- Developed critical features of Ping Pong Fury from initial code through soft-launch.
- Turned TableTennisTouch into a free-to-play game; Bringing legacy code up to date in addition to adding monetisation and analytics systems.
- Maintaining and expanding TableTennisTouch & DartsOfFury, which have over 40 million installs combined.
- Developed a peer-to-peer multiplayer solution with WebRTC across C# .NET, native Android, and native iOS, that drastically cut server costs.
- Developed a client-server multiplayer solution in Go which is optimised for extremely high UDP throughput.

Software Developer

Digisoft.tv 🗷

05/2016 - 05/2018 Media & OTT TV Software Development Cork, Ireland

- Achievements/Tasks
- Lead Android Developer for the EPIC Museum App. 🗗
- Developed the Playmigo casting SDK for Android from prototype to first release. 🗷
- Developed the Roku app in BrightScript for the Playmigo SDK.
- Embedded C/C++ and Java development for set-top boxes as well as relevant server maintenance.

EDUCATION

Computer Games Development

Institute of Technology Carlow

10/2012 - 05/2016

Courses

BSc. First Class Honours

- A course with a strong focus on practicality, effective use of design and programming patterns, and source control.
- Final Year Project A tile-less tower-defence game in C++.
- Graduated at the top of my class.
- ArnieBoids A top-down space shooter in C++ which demonstrates various types of artificial intelligence behaviour.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

Best In Visual Engineering & Best Windows Phone Game (2014)

Games Fleadh

 2 awards for building a VR game with Unity3D for the Durovis Dive headset for Windows Phone

C++ Certified Associate Programmer (2016)

C++ Institute

3rd Place - Robocode Tournament (2013)

Games Fleadh

 Programmed the behaviour of a simulated tank that was pitted against other colleges' entries in free-for-all deathmatches.

INTERESTS

Programming | Strength Training

Dungeons & Dragons

Gaming | Travelling

Japanese Language

Music